Missing audit logs matters because healthcare applications often handle ePHI,
user identity, clinical workflows, patient portals, APIs, and integrations.
Teams should look for this issue in user-facing features, administrative tools,
background jobs, and service-to-service communication.
Poor monitoring matters because healthcare applications often handle ePHI, user identity,
clinical workflows, patient portals, APIs, and integrations.
Teams should look for this issue in user-facing features, administrative tools,
background jobs, and service-to-service communication.
Delayed detection matters because healthcare applications often handle ePHI,
user identity, clinical workflows, patient portals, APIs, and integrations.
Teams should look for this issue in user-facing features, administrative tools,
background jobs, and service-to-service communication.
Insufficient alerting matters because healthcare applications often handle ePHI,
user identity, clinical workflows, patient portals, APIs, and integrations.
Teams should look for this issue in user-facing features, administrative tools,
background jobs, and service-to-service communication.
Centralized logging SIEM integration Security monitoring and alerting Selected HIPAA
mappings for this topic include Section 164.312(b) - Audit controls;
Section 164.308(a)(1)(ii)(D) - Information system activity review.